

# Walter Troiani

Computer & Data Scientist

waltertv02@gmail.com

+34 642 35 60 26

Estartit / Barcelona (Spain)

github.com/eZWALT

walterjtv.tech

www.linkedin.com/in/walterjtv/

MANGO

UPC



#### **About Me**

I'am a highly motivated and disciplined student, currently on the verge of completing my Computer Science degree. I've already gained valuable experience as a dedicated Data Scientist, where my passion for data has flourished. My love for learning drives me to constantly seek new challenges and knowledge, allowing me to stay at the forefront of the latest technological advancements in the field. Ready to embrace new career challenges, excel in demanding roles, and contribute effectively to hardworking teams. With a strong commitment to personal growth and driven to succeed in every endeavor.

### **Personal Projects**

- (Developed in HackUPC 2022)
- Falcon File Explorer (Developed at college, 2023)
- ASL frontend & middle-end compiler (Developed at college, 2023)
- PyTorch / LLVM and more open source contributions!

(Work in progress 2024)

- Deep Learning Calorie calculator APP (Work in progress 2023/24)
- MORE COMING SOON!

## Certifications & Licenses

- Coaching for academic mentoring (UPC, 2021)
- Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera, 2023)
- · AWS cloud practitioner (Work in progress, EDC 6/2024)
- Driving License (Work in progress, EDC 12/2023)

## Languages

- Catalan (Native)
- Spanish (Native)
- English (Advanced)
- Italian (Elementary)

## **Work Experience**

2023 - Now Stager Data Scientist < 1 year

Developed data science applications following the DevOps philosophy using state-of-the-art generative-AI models and classical machine learning models in order to forecast and boost the efficiency of the supply

chain, product personalization and corporate decisions

**FIBVISIONA** 2022- Now Buisness Fair Manager

Coordinated and managed the FibVisiona Forum, a job fair hosting 1 year cutting-edge tech companies. Led advertising, planning, and execution,

fostering valuable connections with industry leaders.

UPC 2021-2023 **Undergraduate Professor** 

2 years Experienced hardware educator at the Aula Lliure project at FIB-UPC. Guided and inspired absolute beginners, nurturing their curiosity and

passion for technology's building blocks

**ARNALL** 2019 - 2022 **Butcher's Shop Assistant** 

Butcher's Shop Assistant ensuring top-notch customer satisfaction through 3 vears

personalized service.

#### **Education**

Computer Science and Engineering 2020-2024

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona) (EAC)

Sant Gabriel Technological Baccalaureate 2018-2020

Graduated with high honors, Col·legi Sant Gabriel (Girona)

#### **Skills & Tools**

- Discipline, perspective, empathy, love for learning, and honesty define my signature traits. Moreover, my exceptional problem-solving skills, abstraction, and critical thinking shape the essence of who I
- · I love working in teams and enjoy taking the lead when the things get stuck or the chance arises. My gentle, outgoing and adaptable nature helps me connect with others effortlessly.
- Proficiency in C/C++/Java/Python/Kotlin
- Familiar with languages such as Haskell/Prolog/Javascript/R/Scala and HTML/CSS frontend
- Experience with assembly languages such as MIPS/x86/ARM and linux environments
- Experienced in C++ libraries such as OpenGL, CUDA, OMP, ANTLR, LLVM
- · Familiar with the postgreSQL language and using MongoDB, S3, DynamoDB, snowflake databases
- Experience developing applications using Infrastructure As Code (IAC) with Terraform/Terragrunt in AWS environment's
- · Used to distributed computing with AWS in a wide range of services: DynamoDB, EC2, S3, ECS .... and a fair amount of experience with Apache PySpark
- Developer experienced in DevOps methodology and CI/CD using technologies as: Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Jira, Confluence, BitBucket, Git (In General) and Airflow
- Self-taught data scientist, comfortable on Jupyter/DataBricks/Colab notebook environments and experienced in diverse libraries such as Pandas, PySpark, Plotly...
- · Hands-on experience in developing projects and applications using machine learning algorithms, some developed with pytorch, tensorflow, scikit-learn, LightGBM, XGBoost, Prophet, LLama2 and other pre-trained generative Al popular models
- · Lifelong learner, always curious and learning about a wide range of different topics such as computer science, data science, AI, cloud computing, algorithmic trading, mathematics and physics on my leisure time

More about me on my personal website walterjtv.tech!